(迈克,本,开萝尔在庭院里扫雪)
(Mike, Ben and Carol cleaning up snow at courtyard)
本:我恨扫雪,我恨扫雪,我恨扫雪.
Ben: I hate this, I hate this, I hate this.
迈克:本尼,就把雪当作食物,
Mike: Bennie, just pretend the snow is your food and that shovel's your fork,
把铲子当作刀叉,那样你就会有干劲了.
you'll do fine.
本:我就不明白我们为什么不让它自己溶化呢?
Ben: I don't see why we don't just let it melt?
开萝尔:溶化?本,这可要好几个星期呢!
Carol: Melt?Ben, that could take days, weeks.
迈克:那样的话,我在想我怎么开车去上学,
Mike: Yeah, then how am I supposed to take my car out to go to school,
为什么不让它自己溶化呢?
I don't see why we just don't let it melt?
开萝尔:你要是不铲,也别指望我再铲了!
Carol: I'm not lifting this shovel again until you start moving some snow.
迈克:哦?我铲!行了吧!
Mike: Oh?I'll move some snow!
本:开萝尔,你快听.
Ben: Hey, Carol.signal, see this.
迈克:来吧!快吃点雪吧!
Mike: Come on, eat this...
(雪仗开始了)
[snow fight starts]
迈克:嘿!
Mike: Hey...
邮递员:打扰一下,我找迈克·西沃,有一份他的邮包,请你在这里签个字.
Mailman: Excuse me?Hey, I am looking for Mike Seaver, I've got a special delivery
package for him.sign here please
迈克:有我的邮件,真是令人难以置信呀!
Mike: Oh, something for me, I can't believe it.
开萝尔:谁怎么会给你写信.
Carol: Yeah, you don't know anyone that can write.
迈克:哇!是水果.
Mike: Wow, fruit?
邮递员:是的,这不单是提货单而是实物,
Mailman: That's right, not just some gift certificate but the real thing,
我拿着这个八磅的东西已经走了两英里.
an 8 pounds bag of pineapples that somebody had to carry for 2 miles.
开萝尔:是从毛利寄来的,我们去年暑假在那里度假.
Carol: Well, it's from Mali, where we were on vacation last summer.
邮递员:算了吧!
Mailman: La-di-da!
迈克:太好了!这是米莉亚寄来的.
Mike: Well, it's from Meliya.
本:米莉亚?是不是就是那个穿比基尼的女孩
Ben: Meliya?Was she the one with the coconut bra?
开萝尔:哈哈哈!迈克,再给我们笑一个!
Carol: Ha ha ha...Mike, show me that smile again.
米莉亚:亲爱的迈克,阿罗哈,这是来自夏威夷的问候,我现在要离开这个岛了,下周末,我要去洛杉矶参加一个导游会议,这真是太令人激动了.
Meliya: Dearest Mike, aloha from Hawaii.I had to let you know that I'm finally
getting off the island.Next weekend, I'll be in Los Angeles for a tour guide
convention, I am so excited.I am 'so' excited
迈克:我也一样.
Mike: Me too.
米莉亚:唯一的遗憾就是,我第一次出来的地方,
Meliya: That's too bad, though,
离你还有三千英里,
my first trip to the mainland is still three thousand miles away from you.
唉!这就是生活.
Well, that's life.Anyway,
不管怎样,
I wanted you to know that someone far away remembers you, very fondly.
你该知道有个人在远方很惦记着你,爱你的米莉亚.
Love, Meliya.
米莉亚:这10天真是有趣呀!我会想你的,
Meliya: It's been such a wonderful 10 days.I am going to miss you.
你什么时候会再来毛利?
When are you coming back to Mali?
迈克:我不知道,你什么时候回来纽约?
Mike: I don't know, when are you coming to New York?
你是不是从没来过纽约?
Ah, you're never coming to New York, are you?
迈克:好吧!忘了纽约吧!
Mike: Well, forget New York, but if you ever make it to the Mainland,
但你如果再来的话,一定得通知我,到时我会去找你的.
I am talking any place you just let me know, and I am there.
米莉亚:好的,迈克.
Meliya: Ha, Mike.
迈克:不,不!我是认真的.
Mike: No, no, I'm serious.
米莉亚:再过二十年你就会把我忘记的.
Meliya: You will forget all about me in 20 years or so.
迈克:哦,决不!
Mike: Ah, No way.
米莉亚:那好,这给你当个留念吧!快过来!
Meliya: Well, just to make sure, here,
迈克:哇!
Mike: Ah, wow!
米莉亚:这是个吉祥项链,紧紧抓住,
Meliya: This is a good-luck charm.
然后许愿,愿望就会实现的.
If you hold it tight and make a wish it'll come true.
迈克:真的吗?
Mike: Really?
米莉亚:下次见到你的时候我再收回来!
Meliya: Next time I see you, I want this back.
迈克:嘘!我在许愿,怎么就不灵呢?
Mike: Hush I am wishing here.It didn't come true.
米莉亚:会显灵的.
Meliya: Yes, it did.
迈克:我想看看你到洛杉矶的机票,
Mike: Yeah, I'd like to check your on flights to Los Angeles.
要那好了!
Aw, hold yourself.
杰森:晚上好,开萝尔.
Jason: Evening, Carol?
开萝尔:爸爸,我知道我回来太晚了,
Carol: Dad, Dad.I know I missed my curfew, but we, I, I am so sorry,
对不起,不过我不会对你撒谎的.
Dad.I can't lie to you.
迈克:开萝尔,你真令我恶心.
Mike: Carol, you disgust me.
开萝尔:迈克?
Carol: Mike?
迈克:你是我的妹妹,应该也会撒谎的呀!
Mike: Look, you know you are my sister.you should be able to lie.
开萝尔:你不会告诉爸妈我回来晚了吧?
Carol: You won't tell Mom and Dad when I came in, will you?
迈克:当然,我会告诉他们的.
Mike: Of course I will.
开萝尔:你要说?
Carol: You will?
迈克:不会了,我只是对你说了个谎,你看说谎不是很容易吗?
Mike: No, that was a lie, see?It's easy.
开萝尔:这么说你不跟爸妈讲了?
Carol: So you won't?
迈克:是的.
Mike: No.
开萝尔:谢谢,迈克!你真好!
Carol: Oh, thanks, Mike, You are so sweet.
迈克:对了,我想问明天有没有到洛杉矶的飞机,
Mike: Yeah, yeah, yeah, here, I'd like to check on your flight to Los Angeles.
星期天回来的那种,
Tomorrow.I'll need to come back on Sunday.And how much is that going to cost?
这大概需要多少钱?这可不是开玩笑.
No, seriously.Hello?
开萝尔:迈克你是不是想飞到洛杉矶看米莉亚?
Carol: Mike, you're flying to California to see Meliya, aren't you?
迈克:不,我不是的.
Mike: No, I am not.
开萝尔:你在说谎吧!你想去买飞机票.
Carol: Now I know that's a lie.You wanted to buy a ticket.
迈克:是的,我想给你买张单程票.
Mike: Yeah, for you.One way.
开萝尔:不,你是想去看米莉亚.
Carol: No, you want to see Meliya!
开萝尔:这真是一件是浪漫的事.
Carol: What a wonderful thing to do.
为了赢得一个女人的爱宁愿抛弃一切,
I mean forgetting everything,
飞越千山万水去找她.这么浪漫的事只有在书里才会读到,
and flying all the way across the country all for the love of a lady.
就是一个有权有势的男子,
This is the kind of romantic things that you only read about,
或是一个公爵某天看到了一个纯朴的女孩,
a rich powerful man, maybe a Duke, one day, he sees the simple peasant girl,
一个真正天真无邪的打水女孩.
not doing anything provocative, just pumping water,
迈克:爸爸知不知道你在看这种书?
Mike: Does Dad know you read this kind of stuff?
开萝尔:他忘不了那个女孩,
Carol: He cannot forget about her.
从那天以后,他愿意为那女孩放弃他的权利,
And from that day on, he is willing to give up his power, his fortune,
财富和他那稳固和强有力的……
and his stable, mighty...
迈克:开萝尔,别提你的公爵了,行不行?
Mike: Carol, forget your duke, all right?
开萝尔:迈克·西沃,能做你的妹妹我真是自豪!
Carol: Mike Seavor, I am proud to be your sister.
迈克:哦,行了!我不要听这些.
Mike: Oh, come on, look, I don't mean that.
开萝尔:怎么了?
Carol: What's wrong?
迈克:我可不象你的公爵那么威风,我现在没有什么钱.
Mike: Well, unlike your stupid duke, and I am little short of funds.
开萝尔:还缺多少钱?
Carol: How short?
迈克:二百七十九美元.
Mike: 279 dollars
开萝尔:票价是多少?
Carol: How much is the ticket?
迈克:二百七十九美元.
Mike: 279 dollars
开萝尔:我的存款超过这个数了.
Carol: I have more than that in my savings account.
迈克:那恭喜你了!
Mike: Congratulations.
开萝尔:迈克,我可以借给你的.
Carol: Mike, I can lend it to you.
迈克:好好好!你肯吗?
Mike: Yeah, Yeah, Yeah, You can?
开萝尔:这是为你的浪漫才借你的.
Carol: It's for romance
迈克:好的,我会尽快还你的.
Mike: Well, I'll pay you back real soon.
开萝尔:这也是一个说谎的机会.
Carol: Don't ruin this moment with a lie.
迈克:好了,也许是几个星期,也许是几个月我就会还你的.
Mike: Ok, ok, maybe weeks, maybe even months before I pay you back.
开萝尔:那就好.
Carol: That's better.
迈克:只要我办得到.
Mike: If I ever do it all.
开萝尔:你可别耍赖呀!
Carol: Don't push it.
迈克:这周末我想去加利福尼亚看看,妈妈,能不能再要些咖啡?
Mike: Now, on this weekend, in California.More coffee, mother?
麦琪:好的.
Maggie: OK
迈克:到时我就能亲身看看那里的全国几所好大学.爸爸,
Mike: I will be able to check some of the finest colleges in the country.
你还要些吗?
Can I freshen that for you Dad?
杰森:不要了.
Jason: No
迈克:加一些吧!
Mike: You got it.
迈克:我是指南加州大学,加州大学洛杉矶分校,还有若斯波尔.
Mike: You know, I mean USC, UCLA, the Ross ball.
麦琪:若斯波尔不是大学,迈克.
Maggie: The Ross ball is not a college, Mike.
迈克:我在我去之前还是最好和你们讲讲.
Mike: Ho, a good thing we had this talk before my trip.
杰森:我猜这可能和米莉亚送你的菠萝有关吧!
Jason: My guess is it that this has something to do with all those pineapples
Meliya sent you?
迈克:好了,我只是来通知你们一下,
Mike: Ok, all right, I, I meant to mention it to guys.
我很忙的,你看我要倒垃圾,
I just got so busy, taking out the trash,
打扫房间,还要倒咖啡.
cleaning my room and pouring the coffee.
杰森:迈克,你一个人完成这样的长途旅行,
Jason: Mike, traveling by yourself on a trip like this is a very big step
就你这种年纪来说是件大事呀!
for somebody of your age.
迈克:可是,
Mike: But, Dad, I mean, when you were 17,
你17岁的时候不是独自骑车去了许多欧洲国家吗?
didn't you bike right through Europe, a whole seperate country, I believe.
迈克:怎么人们总会在这些重要时刻想到一些事呢?
Mike: Why do they always remember these things in a time like this?
麦琪:但是当时你爸爸可不是到欧洲去和女孩约会.
Maggie: But your father didn't go to Europe to meet a girl.
Mike: Oh, sure he did.I mean Beng Beng Na.that you told me all
杰森:不,我什么也没跟你讲呀!
Jason: No, I told you nothing.
杰森:迈克,这次旅行太不切实际了,
Jason: Mike, this trip is impractical for many reasons.
其中的原因很多,比如去那里机票就很贵.
For instance, the air fare to California is very expensive.
迈克:是的,我没钱,但开萝尔会借给我!
Mike: Yeah, yeah, but Carol's lending me the money
杰森:马上给我出去.
Jason: Get out of town.
迈克:谢谢,爸爸.
Mike: Thanks, Dad.
杰森:等等,站在!
Jason: Wait, hold on.
杰森:开萝尔是自愿借给你的吗?
Jason: Carol is doing this of her own free will?
迈克:对的,
Mike: Yeah, yeah, that's right.
是那样的,
She understands that sometimes the duke has to see his peasant girl pumping
开萝尔说公爵有时候得去看他那抽水姑娘.
that water.
迈克:开萝尔讲的比我好多了!
Mike: Well, carol explains a lot better than I do.
麦琪:宝贝,你真的喜欢那姑娘?
Maggie: Honey, you really like this girl?
杰森:麦琪?
Jason: Maggie?
麦琪:杰森,她是真的喜欢那女孩.
Maggie: Jason, he really likes this girl.
杰森:迈克,对不起,我们的回答是不.
Jason: Mike, we are sorry, but the answer is NO.
迈克:得了,得了!爸爸,我接受你们的答复.妈妈,你帮我劝劝爸爸.
Mike: Ok, ok, I accept that, dad.Work on him, mom.
杰森:麦琪,
Jason: Maggie, there is part of me that wants him to go too.
我其实有些同意他去,
I mean you've got to admire a guy who's willing to go to any end,
做任何事都很执着的人我们是应该表扬的,但只要他不把那愚蠢的念头放在女人身上.
and travel any distance just to make a fool of themselves over a woman.
这就像我刚刚那样执着.
Much as I just did it now.
麦琪:杰森,他已经十七岁了.况且他也有了钱,他应该可以和他真正喜爱的姑娘在一起,单独地待上两天,不过迈克,你别太得寸进尺.
Maggie: Jason, he is 17, and he's got the money and he got the chance to
spend 2 days alone with the girl he really really likes.
Not snowball's chance, Mike
开萝尔:迈克,你这下麻烦了,遇到大麻烦了!你还是理智点吧,
Carol: Oh, mike, you get in trouble, big trouble, be logical,
你还是不要去了.但你看来已经决定非去不可了!你这是个浪漫的人.
you cannot do this.But you've got to do this.You are so romantic.
迈克:我是很浪漫的,现在把钱给我吧!
Mike: That's me.hi, now fork over the bucks.
开萝尔:好的,那你怎么打算呢?
Carol: Well, sure, ok what's you plan?
迈克:是的,我准备在纽约上机,然后在洛杉矶下机.
Mike: Well, I get on the plane in New York and I get off in LA.
开萝尔:这就是你的计划?
Carol: You call that a plan?
迈克:那你想让我在哪里下飞机?丹佛吗?
Mike: Then where do you expect me to get off?Denver?
开萝尔:我是说你应该偷偷出去,
Carol: I am just saying that you should work on your cover.
到时你就趁等天黑了之后再溜开.
I mean wait until it is real late, then you sneak out.
开萝尔:我会帮你编个故事说你在波纳家过夜,反正只要他们问起你,
Carol: Have me make up a stories about your being at Boner's house for
我就说你在另外一个房间.
the day.I mean I can always say you are in another room if they ask.
你瞧!我已经会说谎了!
I can lie, I can lie.I can lie!
本:代理人本汇报工作来了,我准备进行我的可可豆计划.
Ben: Agent Ben, Reporting for duty, ready to do my part in operation Coconuts.
开萝尔:迈克的手提袋在哪?
Carol: Where is Mike's Suitcase?
本:我把他藏在垃圾袋里了,哦!不!
Ben: I hid it in this garbage bag.Oh, no.
开萝尔:我看这一切都得看我的安排了.
Carol: I can see this is all going to be left up to me.
本:警服.
Ben: Cop's clothes.
开萝尔:给我.
Carol: Give me that.
本:请批准我去查看黄麻雀的动静吧!
Ben: Requesting permission to go and watch for the yellow bird.
开萝尔:我懒得关你,去吧!
Carol: I don't care, just go.
本:你知不知道黄麻雀是什么意思吗?
Ben: Do you know what the yellow bird is?
开萝尔:肯定很漂亮!现在马上给我出去.
Carol: I am sure, it's nice.Now, get out.
本:是出租车.
Ben: It's the taxi.
开萝尔:别管闲事,快走开.
Carol: Whatever, go.
迈克:开萝尔,妈妈爸爸在楼上.
Mike: Carol, Mom and Dad are upstairs.They don't suspect a thing.
他们根本没察觉到,不要紧张,一切都很好.
Everything can be just fine, and just calm down.
开萝尔:好的!迈克,这是全部的飞机时刻表,那好了!
Carol: Ok all right.Mike.Here are all the flight times, ok?
你要从纽约飞到丹佛,在丹佛停五小时后,再飞往洛杉矶.
You take New York to Denver, and then a 5 hour layover and then into LA.
迈克:要停五小时!我要疯了!
Mike: Five hour layover, that's crazy.
开萝尔:但这样便宜很多.
Carol: But it's cheaper.
迈克:但我可是去约会呀!
Mike: But this is romance.
开萝尔:但这是我的钱.
Carol: This is my money.
迈克:那你真是体贴.
Mike: Self-hurt.
开萝尔:好了,这给你.
Carol: All right.Here it is.
本:代理人本报告,黄麻雀已经着陆,出租车已经来了.
Ben: Agent Ben reporting the yellow bird has landed.The cab is here.
开萝尔:好的.
Carol: OK.
迈克:好了,开萝尔,我要出发了!难道这还不算出发吗?
Mike: All right, Carol, here I go.I haven't moved yet, have I?
开萝尔:迈克,出租车在等你.
Carol: Mike, Cab is waiting.
迈克:好了,开萝尔,
Mike: Ok Carol, maybe its not such a good idea I go.
也许我真不该去.晚上电视还会播杰森·巴特曼主持的健康星期五节目呢!
Jason Bateman's wholesome Friday night video is tonight.
本:八点的节目是哈克雷贝里.
Ben: Huckleberry at 8 o'clock.
开萝尔和迈克:什么?
Carol and Mike: What?
本:爸爸来了,快走!
Ben: Dad is coming, Jee-whizz.
开萝尔:你好,爸爸.
Carol: Hi, Dad.
杰森:你们好,开萝尔,本.我不是叫你把这个拿出的吗?
Jason: Hi, Carol, Ben, I thought I told you to take this out.
本:我在做.
Ben: I did.
杰森:和迈克一起做?那他人呢?
Jason: Mike with you?
本:他不在,就我一人.
Ben: Not anymore.
开萝尔:不,不!他在他房间里.
Carol: No, no, he's in his room
本:是的,车要是不在那他就不在.
Ben: Yeah, his car wouldn't be here if he wasn't in his room.
现在他的车在这里,你明白了吗?
And its here all right, see?
杰森:那是什么意思?
Jason: What's that?
本:什么意思?
Ben: What was what?
杰森:我们到房里说.
Jason: Oh, I'll see you inside.
开萝尔:本,黄麻雀都还没离开笼子,
Carol: Ben, you almost spilt the beans about the operation coconuts to
你就差点把可可豆计划泄漏给了爸爸.
papa bear before yellow bird flew the coop.
开萝尔:迈克?
Carol: Mike?
迈克:还是我先到这里,看你狗急的
Mike: I was in here first, dog breath.
开萝尔:迈克,别乱起绰号.
Carol: Mike, don't call your sister names.
迈克:好吧.
Mike: All right.
开萝尔:妈妈,一上午他都待在这里,
Carol: Mom, he is been in there all morning and says he is going to stay
他说他不想出来吃早饭.
in through breakfast.
麦琪:迈克,你不想吃早饭?
Maggie: Mike, you don't want breakfast?
迈克:妈妈,我不吃早饭了.
Mike: No breakfast this morning, mom.
麦琪:你在里面作什么?
Maggie: What are you doing in there?
迈克:没什么,早饭闻上去不错.
Mike: Whatever it is, it sure smells good.
麦琪:什么?迈克,
Maggie: What?Mike, are you all right?
你不舒服吗?过几分分钟后你就下来,我们在楼下等你.
Oh, well, we'll see you downstairs in a few minutes, ok?
本:嗯……
Ben: Hum...
开萝尔:本,我们怎么可能能让迈克几分钟后出现在楼下呢?
Carol: Ben, how we going go get Mike downstairs in a few minutes?
本:我也不知道.
Ben: I don't know.
开萝尔:早餐真的不错吗?
Carol: Sure smells good?
杰森:这雪还有八英尺厚,看来今天我们有的累了!迈克跑哪里去了?
Jason: Another 8 inches out there.Going to be a lot of shoveling today.Where is
Mike
麦琪:开萝尔说他改变主意了,但他现在不想吃早饭.
Maggie: Carol said he changed his mind, and doesn't feel like breakfast.
杰森:难道他还在为洛杉矶不能成行而生气?
Jason: Still upset about not being able to go to Los Angeles?
开萝尔:不,他已经不生气了.
Carol: No, he is over that.
本:是的,我也看现在他很好.
Ben: Yes, I saw him too, he is fine.
他还是很健谈,事实上我想……
His deep talk, actually, I think he..., au?
开萝尔:你怎么知道的?本,实际上电话是七点五十九响的.
Carol: What do you know?Ben, the telephone rings up 7:59 exactly.
本:哦!
Ben: Oh.
麦琪:开萝尔?
Maggie: Carol?
开萝尔:我去接,喂?
Carol: I got it.Hello?
迈克:我现在正在享受在丹佛的这五个小时,我怎么这么轻讲话呢?
Mike: Yeah, I am really enjoying my 5 hour here in Denver.Why am I whispering?
开萝尔:迈克,你的电话.
Carol: Mike, Telephone.
迈克:我在楼上接.
Mike: I'll take it upstairs.
麦琪:开萝尔,是谁打来的?
Maggie: Carol, who is on the phone?
开萝尔:是迈克,嗯!是波纳打的,迈克从波纳家打电话过来.
Carol: Mike, eh, eh, Boner.He's calling at Boner's house.
杰森:等等,迈克他怎么了?
Jason: Wait a minute.Mike?
迈克:爸爸?
Mike: Dad?
杰森:先生,你没出去吧!
Jason: You are not going anywhere, Mr.
迈克:我没有.
Mike: I am not.
本:爸爸在和谁讲话?
Ben: Who is dad talking to?
开萝尔:迈克.
Carol: Mike.
本:再见.
Ben: Bye.
杰森:别担心,要是他不把雪铲完,他就别想溜走.
Jason: Don't worry; he is not taking off until he does his share of the shovelling.
迈克:爸爸,现在我有点事情.
Mike: Well, dad, that is going to be a little tough.
杰森:迈克,五分钟后到外面来见我,不要再找借口了.波纳,再见!
Jason: Mike, I want to see you outside in five minutes.no excuses.Say good
bye, Boner
迈克:再见,西沃医生.
Mike: Good-bye, Doctor Seavor.
机场播音员:注意了,米莉亚的航班已经到达.你快去接她,迈克!
Airport speaker: Attention, Meliya's flight has now arrived.Go in for it, Mike.
迈克:米莉亚?米莉亚,是我.
Mike: Meliya?Meliya, It's me.
米莉亚:迈克?迈克!
Meliya: Mike?Mike.
迈克:哦,我是做梦也想见到你.
Mike: Oh, I dreamed this would happen.
老妇人:嘿!我是从德克萨斯过来的.
Old lady: Hi, I am from Texas.
本:这人真是太好了.
Ben: The man is good.
开萝尔:太棒了!慢点,我们要让他们以为你是迈克,记住了吗?嘿!波纳.
Carol: Too good.Slow down, we want them to think you are Mike, remember?Hi, Boner?
波纳:嘘!我是迈克,不记得了?
Boner: Hush, I am Mike, remember?
开萝尔:把你的连遮起来.
Carol: Keep your face covered.
波纳:好的.
Boner: Ooops.
开萝尔:你就像平常一样铲雪,好吗?
Carol: Just try in shovel like a normal person, ok?
波纳:一定会的.
Boner: Do what I can.
麦琪:杰森,迈克在那里拼命地扫雪.
Maggie: Jason, Mike has been out there shoveling like a man possessed.
杰森:毕竟是到忘记电话里那无聊念头地时候了!
Jason: After all that nonsense on the phone about his trying to get out of it.
麦琪:真是真有趣!你以为你很了解孩子们,但他们却常常让你吃惊.要不要来杯热可可.
Maggie: Oh, that's funny.Just when you think you know your kids, they surprise you.Hot chocolate!
本:好的.
Ben: All right!
波纳:哇!
Boner: Wow.
开萝尔:谢谢!妈妈.
Carol: Thanks, mom.
麦琪:迈克?行了,特别是你需要休息一下.
Maggie: Mike?Oh, come on, you especially deserve a break.
波纳:这味不错,就是有点淡.
Boner: Not bad.A little fuzzy.
机场播音员:现在来自夏威夷火努鲁鲁的122次航班已经到达,在二十四号门下机.
Airport speaker: Now arriving, Flight 122 from Honolulu, Hawaii, gate 24
迈克:米莉亚?米莉亚,是我.
Mike: Meliya?Meliya, It's me.
米莉亚:迈克?迈克,哈哈!
Meliya: Mike?Mike?Ha ha,
迈克:嘿!你看上去不太一样.
Mike: Hey, You look so different.
米莉亚:你在这里做什么?
Meliya: What are you doing here?
迈克:你认为呢?
Mike: Well, what do you think?
米莉亚:严肃点!你在这里做什么?
Meliya: Seriously, what are you doing here?
迈克:我在这里做什么?我来这里看你呀!
Mike: What I am doing?I am here to see you.
米莉亚:行了,你大老远从纽约过来只是想看我.
Meliya: Come on, you came all the way from New York just to see me?
迈克:是的,现在我刚好又成了你的邻居啦!
Mike: Yeah, well, I just happened to be your neighborhood.
米莉亚:迈克,你该事先告诉我的.
Meliya: Mike, you should tell me you are coming.
迈克:我说过的,不记得了吗?是我们在夏威夷的最后那个晚上.
Mike: Well, I did.Remember?Our last night in Hawaii?
米莉亚:但这个周末我都要开会.
Meliya: But I got this convention business all weekend.
迈克:啊……
Mike: Ah...
米莉亚:迈克,你应该理解我,我也没办法.
Meliya: Mike, you've got to understand.It's not like I can just...
迈克:现在你就别提那会议了.
Mike: Just forget your whole convention and everything?
米莉亚:好的.明天有个闭幕晚宴,
Meliya: exactly.Well, there is going to be a closing banquet tomorrow night.
我能拿到额外的票,你会来吗?
I can get an extra ticket.Would you want to go?
迈克:呃……明晚?
Mike: Er... tomorrow night?
米莉亚:真对不起,
Meliya: Oh, I feel so terrible.You flew all the way here just to see me.
你飞这么远就是想在机场见我一面.
And booked.
迈克:不,不是这样的
Mike: Oh, no, I didn't.
米莉亚:你不是的?
Meliya: You didn't?
迈克:不是的,我不知道!我是来看看大学的,什么南加州大学,加州大学洛杉矶分校,还有若斯波尔之类的.
Mike: Oh, no.I don't know.Heck no.I was going to check out the
colleges, you know the ULA.UC IC and Rose Bud
米莉亚:若斯波尔!
Meliya: Rose Bud.
迈克:能见到你真开心!好了,
Mike: Yeah, it's a great interview.Well, anyway, I've to get back on my plane.
我的飞机可能还有10分钟就要飞了,只有5分钟了,我得马上走.
It leaves about in 10 minutes.Oh, five minutes.Oh real soon.
米莉亚:哦,我明白.
Meliya: Oh, I see.
迈克:我只想能找个机会来看看你,问候一下你,
Mike: well, I just want to make sure that I got a chance to come out
现在我做到了.是的,我做到了.
here and see you and say hello.And I did.Hello.And I said it again.
米莉亚:迈克,我……
Meliya: Mike, I ...
迈克:不,不!我必须得走了!我的飞机马上要起飞了,再见!
Mike: No, no.I've got to go.My plane is going to leave here.Bye.
米莉亚:再见!
Meliya: Bye.
杰森:本,能不能叫迈克来吃饭?
Jason: Ben, will you call Mike to dinner?
本:迈克·西沃?
Ben: Mike Seavor?
杰森:不是都是一个人吗?
Jason: Yeah, that's the one.
本:我看上去像知道他在哪里的人吗?
Ben: Well, do I look like I know where he is?
杰森:本,这件事还没结束吗?
Jason: Ben, is something going on?
本:开萝尔可能知道.
Ben: Carol might know.
开萝尔:知道什么?
Carol: Know what?
本:就是迈克到底在哪!
Ben: Where the heck Mike is.
开萝尔:是的,迈克说他去波纳家吃晚饭了.
Carol: Well, he told me he was going over to Boner's house for dinner.
麦琪:杰森,你有没有叫迈克铲后院的雪.
Maggie: Jason, did you ask Mike to shovel the backyard?
杰森:后院?你是说我们的草坪.
Jason: The backyard - you mean the lawn?
麦琪:他一直都铲到车道那边了,
Maggie: He hit the edge of the driveway, and keep right on going.
现在干净得我们都可以在外面玩磓球了.
We could play Croquet out there!
杰森:今天一天他都在铲雪,我真的有点为他担心!
Jason: He has been shoveling all day.I'm worried about him.
开萝尔:好了!,你们知道什么?看来迈克爱上铲雪了!对吧?本.
Carol: Well, well, well.What do you know?It looks like Mike has got new
hobby, eh Ben
本:我什么也不知道,我什么也没讲.
Ben: I don't know nothing on him, not saying a word.
要是你再打我,我就要你.
If you hit me again, I will bite you.
波纳:现在很干净吧?
Boner: Is it clear?
开萝尔:波纳,你在干什么?他们会发觉的.
Carol: Boner, What are you doing here?They'll find out!
波纳:我是来还迈克的衣服的.
Boner: I'm just returning Mike his clothes!
杰森:迈克?是迈克吗?迈克·西沃?
Jason: Mike?Is Mike in here?Mike Seavor?
本:不,他不在,这是真的.
Ben: No, he isn't, and that's the truth.
本:快躲起来!
Ben: Let's hide!
开萝尔:天呀!
Carol: God, Yeah!
麦琪:迈克?
Maggie: Mike?
迈克:哦,嘿!妈妈.
Mike: Oh, hi, Mom.
麦琪:迈克,你回来来.
Maggie: Mike, here you are.
本:是的,他回来来啦!就像今天我说的,为什么我想他……
Ben: Yeah, there he is, just like I've been saying all day.Why I think he...
开萝尔:本,不用再讲了,我想大家也都饿了.迈克,你也俄了吧,没在飞机上吃点东西?
Carol: Ben, Ben, Ben.There's no reason to go over all that.I mean everybody
is hungry!I am hungry.Mike you are hungry, or did you eat on the
plane
杰森:迈克?
Jason: Mike?
迈克:是的,我在屋里,爸,现在我哪也不去了.
Mike: Yes, still here, Dad.Grounded, I am not going to any place.
杰森:我想看看你现在是高兴还是失望.
Jason: Just want to check if it was Live or Memorex.
迈克:一点也不高兴!
Mike: You don't feel very alive, Dad.
爸,这是我一生中最糟糕的一天,
This has been the worst day in my entire life.
我被一个女孩回绝了,
I mean I have been rejected by a girl.
我被罚一个月内不能开车,
I got my car ticket away for a month.
另外还欠开萝尔两百七十九美元,
Plus I owe Carol 279 dollars, plus interest.
还加利息,不过利息她没提.
She never even mentioned that interest here.
我真不该开始这次愚蠢的旅行.
I wish I hadn't gone on this stupid trip.
杰森:还记得我去欧洲旅行的事吗?
Jason: Remember what I told you about my trip to Europe,
其实是去见一个叫米蒂姑娘.
to meet Mindy what's her name?
迈克:就是那个诺特人!
Mike: Notman.
杰森:是诺特人.我一共花了四百零七美元的机票费,六十四美元的超车罚款,其他还花了八十四美元.可是你知道她说了什么?
Jason: Notman.Yeah.But you know, after spending 407 dollars for the air fares.63 dollars on the ten speed, 84 dollars on assorted sundries.you know what she told me
迈克:什么?
Mike: What?
杰森:她说希望我们永远是好朋友.
Jason: She said I just hope we will always be good friends.
迈克:哦!
Mike: Oh.
杰森:是的,明显她是认为我太穷了.
Jason: Yeah.Evidently, she didn't take my sundries were that well assorted.
迈克:为什么?爸爸,为什么我们都这么做呢?
Mike: Why, Dad, why do we do it?
杰森:想听听我的专业性意见吗?
Jason: Want my professional opinion?
迈克:是的.
Mike: Yeah.
杰森:男人都是很傻的.
Jason: Men are nuts.
失恋也比不会爱要强,
Or maybe it really is true that it's better to have loved and lost than
这句话讲的太对了.
never to have loved at all.
迈克:是的,你该马上写下来.
Mike: How well, you ought to write that down.
杰森:我已经写下了,迈克.
Jason: It's already been written down, Mike.
从某意义上讲,每个男人都要在一个女人面前当次笨蛋,只是你可能当的早了一些.
Every guy I know at some point or another ends up making a chump of himself
晚安,迈克.
over a woman.Maybe you just got through it early.Good night, Mike.
迈克:嘿爸?你觉得你去见米蒂值吗?
Mike: Hey Dad?Was your trip to see Mellia worth it?
杰森:比今天的钱多,不过值得.
Jason: Not today's prices.But, erm, yeah.
(音乐响起)
(Music)
杰森:今晚真是过的不错,联邦航天局着陆的飞机还没我教育的小孩多呢!
Jason: What a night.
麦琪:对啊!大家好像都为这事着急,
I've grounded more kids tonight than the FAA has grounded planes.
也不知道怎么应付,照我看,根本没什么好担心着急的.
Maggie: Yeah, well.It looks like everyone involved in this mess hass been
你好!波纳.
caught and dealt with, and that is just fine with me,
00:22:26,600
because I have had enough surprises.Hi, Boner.